Alex Ross

San Jose, CA | Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

Summary

After four years of studying to become a Physical Therapist, I decided to pursue my passion for programming and have loved it ever since. I will be attending San Jose State University in Spring 2024 to continue learning as a developer and complete my B.S. in **Software Engineering**. I am currently seeking **internships** as a **front-end** or **full-stack** developer. However, I am always open to other opportunities will allow me to learn new technologies and evolve as a developer.

SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, Python, SQL, C, ARM Assembly

Frameworks: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, MariaDB

Developer Tools: Git, GitHub, Postman, VS Code, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Vercel Libraries: Framer Motion, React Email, Resend, React DnD, Chakra UI

Education

San Francisco State University, 3.9 GPA

B.S. in Kinesiology (incomplete)

West Valley College, 4.0 GPA

Computer Science

Jan. 2021 - Jun. 2022 Saratoga, CA

San Francisco, CA

Aug. 2022 - Dec. 2023

All Lower Division Courses completed. Includes: OOP, D.S., & Algorithms w/ Java, C & ARM Assembly Programming.

Projects

CineFind (Personal Project) | Node.js, React, Express.js, MongoDB | [Website] [Code]

Jun. 2023 - Oct. 2023

- Developed a **REST API** served by Express.js that collects and stores data with MongoDB.
- Implemented CRUD operations as well as user authentication using JWT.
- Stored secure passwords in MongoDB using hashing functions from **bcrypt**.
- Integrated React features such as the React Context API, custom hooks, React DOM, and more.
- Utilized popular React libraries such as React Router, React Loading Skeleton, React DnD, and more.
- Designed fully **responsive** layouts for every page.
- Deployed server-side API and the client-side React-App to Vercel.

Personal Portfolio (Personal Project) | Next.js, TypeScript, React, TailwindCSS | [Website] [Code]

Oct. 2023

- Applied new Next.js features including **App Router** and **Server Actions**.
- Optimized the UI with features such as Framer Motion, the Intersection Observer API, and React Hot Toast.
- Created a contact form that implements React Email and Resend to format and receive e-mails from recruiters.
- Leveraged TailwindCSS features to implement a **theme** switcher.
- Hosted on Vercel.

Temperature Analysis (School Project) | C, MariaDB, SQL, Linux | [Code]

May 2023

- Wrote a C program to collect and validate temperature data from a sensor and store the data in MariaDB.
- Built a terminal application that allows a user to analyze that data utilizing **SQL** queries.

Work Experience

Theatre Manager, Human Resources

AMC Theatres

Mar. 2022 - Sep. 2022

San Jose, CA

- Led a team of 30+ employees to deliver a 99% guest approval rating.
- Delivered essential HR functions including recruiting, scheduling, and payroll, netting \$20,000 in budget savings.

Physical Therapy Aide

Jan. 2022 - May 2022

South City PT

- San Francisco, CA • Collaborated with the lead Physical Therapist in creating rehabilitation plans for clients.
- Provided individualized care to patients and educated them on their rehab exercises.